<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: impress.js | [Zero setLogger: self];]]></title>
  <link href="http://itszero.github.com/blog/categories/impress-js/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://itszero.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-01T11:37:13-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://itszero.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chien-An "Zero" Cho]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trying out the impress.js]]></title>
    <link href="http://itszero.github.com/blog/2012/01/06/try-out-impress-js/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-06T02:25:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://itszero.github.com/blog/2012/01/06/try-out-impress-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is a interesting javacsript library being released on the github these
days, the <a href="http://bartaz.github.com/impress.js/">impress.js</a>. Impress.js is a
framework for making presentations on a open canvas, or so called the
<a href="http://prezi.com">Prezi-style</a>. I tried out the Prezi few years ago. It's
cool, but as the README from the impress.js said: ``impress.js may not help you
if you have nothing interesting to say ;)''. I don't really have a chance to
make a will-use-on-the-stage presentation on a Prezi.</p>

<p>Fortunately, there is a regular meeting of my lab, and it's just my turn to
present a read paper this week. I spent a whole night and messed around with
the impress.js. You can find my result here: <a href="/attic/dynamic-ua-for-wsn/">A dynamic user authentication
scheme for wireless sensor network</a>. I'm not really
get used to arrange contents flat, so the result is not perfect yet.</p>

<p><a href="/images/impressjs<em>dynamic</em>ua.png" class="fancybox"><img src="/images/impressjs<em>dynamic</em>ua.png" width="600" title="&quot;A presentation made using impress.js&quot;" ></a></p>

<p>It's really fun to make slides using HTML5/CSS3, and make them <em>alive</em> through
impress.js. For example, I made that Smartcard entirely in the CSS3, which used
border-radius and linear-gradient properties. I also used some CSS3 animation
property in the Security Analysis section. Once you enter the slide, <em>Login
Replay</em> becomes larger and the other two fade out. Next slide zooms in on the
detail of login replay, the text will rotate for a little bit to give you a
visual clue. You can use whatever CSS3 trick you know to make a presentation.
Best of it? You can host it on whatever provider you want since it's just some
plain HTML/CSS/JS files. Dropbox? Sure. Github? Done.</p>

<p>However, it does have some strange quirk. First, the relative location and
zoom-on-active of slides seems not necessarily remain constant across
different computer / resolution / browser configuration set. My slides did
need some tweak to make sure no text being blocked out on both my iMac 27&quot; and
MacBook Air 13&quot;. You'll need to manually align your slides to the center, so
you can expect some negative values on X, Y values. It would be awesome if the
library can take care of this of me. :P</p>

<p>In any case, this is still a fascinating library worth you to play with.
Get it now on the github and perhaps you can make your own slides, or
better, contribute some patches back to the project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
